

TRAVIS GERKE, SCD

Data Science Leader

@ travisgerke@gmail.com

in travisgerke tgerke

J +01-706-346-4899 travisgerke.com San Diego, CA

Google Scholar

EDUCATION

Doctor of Science (ScD) **Epidemiology**

i Harvard School of Public Health

= 2014

Master of Arts (AM) **Biostatistics**

1 Harvard University

2011

Bachelor of Science (BS), Bachelor of Arts (BA) Statistics, Mathematics

1 University of Florida

2009

SKILLS

GitHub

Biostatistics

Machine Learning

MTFX

Causal Inference

I apply my 15+ years of R development experience in the domains of data engineering, machine learning, and biostatistics. I enjoy championing welldocumented and version controlled pipelines at all stages of analysis, from data generation through reporting and visualization.

ACHIEVEMENTS

80+ peer-reviewed publications >2000 citations, h-index 26

Activity on 15 funded grants Funders include NIH, NCI, American Cancer Society, and Department of Defense

85+ presentations and invited seminars

Spans local and international conferences, workshops, and other outreach

SUMMARY & OBJECTIVE

As a practictioner of servant leadership, I balance roles as an independent contributor against that of a full stack data science mentor. I use my experience as a former academic to guide best research and data practice in oncology clinical trials and the real-world evidence domain.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Director of Data Science | The Prostate Cancer Clinical Trials Consortium (PCCTC)

Jun 2021 - Present

Remote

- Established the data science program and recruited top talent to develop modern clinical trial reporting and analytics workflows
- Construct SOPs pertaining to software development life cycles and validation, statistical analysis plans, regulatory-grade data governance, and compliant data engineering (e.g. versioned SDTM/ADaM data stores)
- Led development of custom solutions for patient profile and safety reporting, portfolio tracking, and data quality monitoring

Director of Health Informatics | Moffitt Cancer Center

May 2020 - Jun 2021

Tampa, FL

- Transformed the data access layer as the agile product owner of cloud-based data marts (AWS/Snowflake) and associated informatics tools (R/Python/Shiny)
- Lead teams to provide the foundation for predictive analytics, production-grade ML/Al applications, and data sharing partnerships

Scientific Director of Collaborative Data Services and Assistant Member | Moffitt Cancer Center

May 2016 - May 2020

Tampa, FL

- Provide scientific and technical leadership for Moffitt's data provisioning hub
- Direct academic research lab with emphasis in reproducible data science for realworld evidence studies

Visiting Scientist | Harvard School of Public Health

Nov 2014 - Jul 2020

Boston, MA

 Serve as lead statistician in an epidemiology lab, ensuring appropriate application of statistical methods and providing mentorship of students/postdocs

Assistant Professor of Epidemiology | University of Florida

Sep 2014 - May 2016

Gainesville, FL

• Direct research lab with emphasis in machine learning and causal inference in oncology studies of gene expression